Finding Aid for the Los Angeles Unified School District Board of Education Records LSC.1923
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Minutes, 1875-2009
  - Los Angeles Unified School District, 1875 May 19-2009 June 23
    - Board Reports, 1989 May 11-1989 June 15 (Box 662)
      On June 12, 1989, Mr. Furutani on behalf of Ms Goldberg, Ms. Korenstein and himself, noticed a resolution that the Board invite UTLA and all appropriate parent, labor, administrator, community and student organizations to co-sponsor a Districtwide conference on Shared Decision Making and Site Based Management. The President assigned the resolution to the Educational Development and Student Life Committee.
    - Board Reports, 1989 June 19-1989 June 29 (Box 663)
      On June 19, 1989, the Board adopted Ms. Goldberg's resolution that the Board formally adopt the principles and strategies delineated in the English-Language Arts Framework for the State of California and further, direct the Office of Instruction to assist with the implementation of literature-based/content-based integrated language arts programs in every classroom in the District.
    - Board Reports, 1989 July 10-1989 August 21 (Box 664)
      At the July 10, 1989 Annual Meeting, the Board elected Ms. Jackie Goldberg as President for the 1989-90 fiscal year. Ms. Walters stated that she could not vote for Ms. Goldberg because of the singling out of District administrators for disparate treatment and expressed concern for the morale of the District. Ms. Goldberg stated her expectation that 1989-90 would be remembered as the year of student achievement and emphasized that the District should become more student centered. The July 10, 1989 Minutes contain a special report on the District's fiscal status that includes description of the June 26 adoption of the $3.8 billion dollar Tentative Budget for 1989-90, the largest budget in the District's history.
    - Board Reports, 1989 August 28-1989 September 25 (Box 665)
      On September 25, 1989, Student Member Alfredo Hernandez expressed concern regarding the role students would have in the Shared Decision Making Process and requested that information regarding shared decision making be more readily available to students. Mr. Thompson noted that the next training session would include student representatives.
    - Board Reports, 1989 October 2-1989 November 13 (Box 666)
      On October 23, 1989, the Board unanimously adopted Ms. Weintraub's resolution that the Board strongly urge the State Board of Education to oppose the inclusion of creationism in the Science Framework and to adopt the framework as proposed by the Curriculum Development and Supplemental Materials Commission. On October 30, 1989, Mr. Furutani commented on a special graduation for the Los Angeles High School 1942 senior class of Japanese-American ancestry who were denied diplomas.
    - Board Reports, 1989 November 20-1989 December 15 (Box 667)
      On December 4, 1989, Ms. Goldberg called on Student Member Sonja Mason from Dorsey High School. Ms. Mason voiced concerns on the maintenance of lighting fixtures in classrooms, the use of closed classrooms, locked sanitary facilities and unclear water from drinking fountains.
    - Board Reports, 1990 January 4-1990 January 29 (Box 668)
      On January 16, 1990, Student Member Sofia Paiz expressed students' concerns on overcrowding, classes that are too large, the lack of time for teachers to meet with individual students, scheduling, lack of seats and materials, class programming problems and the lack of time available for counselors to meet with students.
      On January 16, 1990, the Board unanimously adopted Ms. Walters' resolution that Administrative Region C Ethnic Center located at Seventy-Fifth Street School be converted to a parent/community center with the primary purpose of enhancing parent involvement in South Central Los Angeles, and that the name be changed to the "Lucinda Clark Parent/Community Center" to become operational July 1, 1990.
    - Board Reports, 1990 February 5-1990 February 26 (Box 669)
      On February 5, 1990, the Superintendent made a statement concerning the District's critical student housing situation and presented 19 recommendations to the Board for immediate action so that staff will have the direction and authority to respond toward the satisfactory housing of all students.
    - Board Reports, 1990 March 5-1990 April 2 (Box 670)
      On March 19, 1990, President Goldberg welcomed Student Member Juan Carlos Cortez from Venice High School who expressed concern regarding the lack of curriculum to promote pride in a student's heritage, limited information available to bilingual students related to curriculum and graduation requirements and the unavailability of counselors to encourage a student's pursuit of higher education.
      On April 2, 1990, Ms. Walters stated she had received a photograph of a swastika painted on the wall of a District school, as well as a sticker that was on that wall which read, "Niggers get out." Walters asked that the District have workshops in human relations and to have teachers assert that the District will not tolerate such manifestations.
    - Board Reports, 1990 April 16-1990 May 7 (Box 671)
      On April 30, 1990, the Board adopted Ms. Weintraub's resolution that the Superintendent be directed to review the terms of the District's 1980 Consent Decree designed to improve the promotional opportunities for women in certificated administrative positions and with the assistance of legal counsel, recommend a proposal for the continuance of the programs and policies established by the Decree to the fullest extent permitted by the law.
    - Board Reports, 1990 May 14-1990 June 18 (Box 672)
      On May 14, 1990, the Board adopted Mr. Furutani's amended resolution that the Superintendent direct staff to look into the possible problems and their solutions as related to the timely translation and availability of information and applications in languages other than English.
    - Board Reports, 1990 June 21-1990 July 30 (Box 673)
      The June 25, 1990 Minutes contain a copy of the Proposed Integration Program Changes for 1990-91 within the Committee of the Whole Report No. 2.
    - Board Reports, 1990 August 1-1990 September 17 (Box 674)
      On September 10, 1990, the Board adopted Mr. Furutani's resolution that the Board direct the Superintendent to implement, in the Spring of 1991, a ten-week ethnic studies course to be added to the list of options in District graduation requirements. Mr. Sal B. Castro, representing the Mexican American Education Commission, addressed the Board prior to the vote on Mr. Furutani's motion.
    - Board Reports, 1990 September 24-1990 November 26 (Box 675)
      On November 19, 1990, Superintendent Anton made a statement about a lesser known portion of the mandates to State schools under Proposition 98 which requires each school district to prepare and make available to the public, an annual school-accountability report. He added that the report would provide more information to parents and the public about District schools.
    - Board Reports, 1993 March 1-1993 April 19 (Box 676)
      On March 1, 1993, the Board adopted Mr. Slavkin's resolution that the Board immediately convene an Emergency Task Force on Youth Violence and charge this Task Force with the responsibility of developing specific recommendations for the Board and all other appropriate governmental agencies within 30 days. At a special meeting on March 25, 1993, the Board adopted Board of Education Report No. 1, Decision on the Open School Charter Petition. A copy of this Report is attached to these Minutes.
    - Board Reports, 1993 April 26-1993 June 14 (Box 677)
      On May 3, 1993, the Board adopted President Quezada's resolution that the Board declare the first Wednesday in June beginning this year as Cesar Chavez day for the L.A.U.S.D. At a special meeting on May 10, 1993, the Board received Board of Education Report No. 1, Los Angeles Educational Alliance for Restructuring Now (LEARN) Plan Phase I - List of Selected Schools. The Superintendent noted that on March 15 the Board adopted the LEARN Plan which is the framework for restructuring the District.
    - Board Reports, 1993 June 21-1993 July 26 (Box 678)
      On June 21, 1993, numerous groups and individuals recognized Roberta Weintraub's fourteen years of service to the students of the District. Former Board member and 13th District Los Angeles City Councilperson-elect Jackie Goldberg presented Ms. Weintraub with long-stemmed roses and on behalf of the Los Angeles City Council, Superintendent Thompson presented Ms. Weintraub with a resolution by Councilwoman Rita Walters.
    - Board Reports, 1993 August 16-1993 October 11 (Box 679)
      On September 7, 1993, the Board adopted Mr. Slavkin's resolution that the Board receive the recommendations of the Emergency Task Force on Youth Violence, direct the Superintendent to return to the Board within 60 days a suggested action plan for implementation and that the Superintendent be directed to work with City and County agencies to develop educational placements for the supervision and rehabilitation of minor students who are expelled for bringing guns to school.
      On October 4, 1993, the Board adopted Ms. Castro and Ms. Korenstein's resolution that the Superintendent be directed to implement a policy that all school police officers assigned as resident campus police officers at District middle and high schools be in full police uniform, effective immediately.
    - Board Reports, 1993 October 18-1993 December 16 (Box 680)
      On November 29, 1993, the Board held a special meeting for a public hearing concerning the State Waiver Application for Use of Four Pupil-free Days to Implement Limited English Proficient (LEP) Training Program. The Superintendent explained that the District would request a waiver to allow the use of four pupil-free days to conduct a State Department of Education required LEP training program at 79 schools. He stated that the District had been found to be non-compliant with State mandates at the secondary school level in regard to the LEP program and was now required to comply or risk losing $60 million.
    - Board Reports, 1994 January 3-1994 April 11 (Box 681)
      On January 21, 1994, the Board held a special meeting to discuss the impact of the Northridge earthquake on District schools. President Quezada added that the purpose of this meeting is to focus on the needs of the District and commented that preliminary estimates place the possible financial setback as high as $700 million. On January 27, 1994, the Board held a special meeting for an update on the impact of the Northridge earthquake on District schools. President Quezada commented on the recent visit of President Bill Clinton, United States Secretary of Education Richard Riley and today's visit to the Hyde Park School by First Lady Hillary Clinton. President Quezada introduced California State Controller Gray Davis who presented a check for $10 million to address the District's earthquake damage needs.
    - Board Reports, 1994 April 18-1994 June 27 (Box 682)
      On April 18, 1994, the Board discussed Office of the Superintendent Report No. 1, Proposed Expansion of Magnet Programs for 1993-94 and 1994-95. President Quezada expressed concern over the lack of equitable distribution of magnet centers throughout the District and the Superintendent indicated that court-ordered mandates as well as policy issues guided the placement of students.
      On May 2, 1994, the Board supported Mrs. Boudreaux's motion that the Board activate the publication, The Children Can No Longer Wait, with funding for implementation. On May 16, 1994, the Board adopted Mr. Horton's resolution that the Board "commit itself to doing whatever it can to ensure that per pupil spending in California's K-12 public schools is raised to the national average by 1999 by whatever means necessary."
    - Board Reports, 1994 July 11-1994 September 26 (Box 683)
      On August 15, 1994, the Board adopted Ms. Quezada's resolution that the Board go on record opposing Proposition 187 also known as the Save Our State (SOS) initiative. Ms. Quezada's resolution explains that a major component of this proposal would make undocumented immigrants ineligible for enrollment at public elementary and secondary schools and would impose verification and reporting requirements on school districts. On September 19, 1994, Student Member Alejandra Moreno from Hollywood High School expressed students' concerns regarding the adverse effects Proposition 187 would have on students if enacted and stressed the importance of voting by eligible students.
    - Board Reports, 1994 October 3-1994 December 12 (Box 684)
      On October 3, 1994, the Board adopted Mrs. Boudreaux's resolution that the Board "enthusiastically endorse the participation of every member of the school and larger community in the 'Books Brighten Youth Life' campaign to build a legacy of literacy, library use and achievement for our students." On October 17, 1994, Mr. Horton applauded the Gay and Lesbian Education Commission for sponsorship of the Second Annual Gay, Lesbian and Bisexual Youth Conference held Saturday at Occidental College.
    - Board Reports, 1995 January 9-1995 March 30 (Box 685)
      On January 23, 1995, the Board adopted Mrs. Boudreaux's and Mr. Furutani's resolution that the Board strengthen its existing policy to ensure that the ethnically diverse community served by the District and women are fairly represented in any contractor's/subcontractor's work force, consistent with the District's 50% minority work force utilization goal on all construction contracts.
      In response to a "heinous crime" against a kindergarten student at 66th Street School on January 24, 1995, the Board adopted Mrs. Boudreaux, Mr. Horton and Ms. Quezada's resolution that the Superintendent direct all schools to immediately implement a policy that all students seeking permission to leave their classrooms or other supervised activity, shall be accompanied by one or more students as appropriate.
    - Board Reports, 1995 April 3-1995 June 20 (Box 686)
      On May 8, 1995, the Board held a special meeting to discuss, amend and adopt Board of Education Report No. 2, Los Angeles Educational Alliance for Restructuring Now (LEARN) Schools for Phase Three Implementation.
      On June 12, 1995, Mr. Horton commented on the 2nd Annual Gay Prom held at the Omni Sheraton Hotel at no cost to the District.
      On June 19, 1995, Student Member Jessica Saint Paul from Bravo Medical Magnet shared concerns regarding the distribution of condoms in the schools, the uncertainty of graduation for seniors given finals the day before graduation and the need for college scholarships and financial aid for higher education.
    - Legal Board Reports, 1995 June 26-1995 September 18 (Box 687)
      On July 24, 1995, the Board adopted Mr. Horton's resolution that the Board join the Emergency/Coalition to Save Los Angeles in its effort to avoid massive County service reductions and layoffs and that the Board request that the California Legislature adopt the measures requested to meet the needs of County residents and to fully fund public education.
      On August 7, 1995, the Board adopted Mr. Horton's resolution that the Superintendent review the existing District memo on pregnant and parenting teens to ensure the rights of these students under Title IX and to eliminate any unlawful barrier to school continuation for this population of young women.
      On September 5, 1995, President Slavkin reported that the Board will review staff prepared criteria regarding legislative proposals to break-up the District.
    - Legal Board Reports, 1995 September 18-1995 November 6 (Box 688)
      On October 16, 1995, the Board adopted Mrs. Boudreaux's resolution that the Parent Collaborative be formally identified as one of the District's reorganized organizations and that it be an invited presenter at the beginning of the first regular Board meeting of the month. On May 2, 1994, the Board adopted the L.A.U.S.D. restructuring plan and from this action, the Parent Community Services Branch established the Parent Collaborative to provide a regular District parent forum.
    - Legal Board Reports, 1995 November 13-1996 January 22 (Box 689)
      On November 20, 1995, student Board member Quynh Dang from Los Angeles High School expressed equity concerns regarding her school being on a year round multitrack calendar. She explained that classes are not open to all students on all tracks; Honors Advanced Placement classes are offered only on C-track and are unavailable to students on other tracks.
      On November 20, 1995, President Slavkin called on Mr. Richard Mason, General Counsel to report on a Proposition 187 Federal Court development. Mason explained that because of the United States Supreme Court's decision in Plyler v. Doe, related to the obligations of school districts to educate children regardless of their immigration status, the Federal Court in Los Angeles concluded that Federal Law preempts the K-12 portions of Proposition 187.
    - Legal Board Reports, 1996 January 22-1996 March 14 (Box 690)
      On January 22, 1996, the Board adopted Mr. Tokofsky's precatory motion that the Board support the continued operation of the juvenile probation camps and urge the Los Angeles County Board of Supervisors to identify funding needed to prevent the closure of the probation camps.
      On February 20, 1996, the Board adopted Mr. Horton's resolution that the Board support the concept of high school magnet programs jointly supported by the Los Angeles Police Department and the District to prepare students for careers in law enforcement.
      On February 26 and March 14, 1996, the Board held special meetings for action upon the proposed Consent Decree in the case of Chanda Smith, et al. v. LAUSD, et al.. In November 1993 this class action lawsuit was filed against the District on behalf of students with disabilities alleging that the District had failed to search for, identify, track, and timely and properly serve the educational needs of students with disabilities in violation of federal law.
    - Legal Board Reports, 1996 March 18-1996 May 28 (Box 691)
      On March 18, 1996, the Board adopted Mr. Horton's precatory motion that the Board go on record in support of the Living Wage Act of 1996 Ballot Initiative and other efforts to increase the minimum wage.
      On May 6, 1996, the Board adopted Mr. Horton's amended resolution that the Board go on record in support of the Labor/Community Strategy Center and the Bus Riders Union civil rights class action lawsuit against the MTA for engaging in policies and practices which result in disparate impact on racial minorities in violation of Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964.
    - Legal Board Reports, 1996 June 3-1996 August 5 (Box 692)
      On June 3, 1996, the Board adopted Mr. Kiriyama's motion regarding continued support for character education and Mrs. Boudreaux's motion that Board Rule 1995 be amended to change the name of the Sex Equity Commission to the Gender Equity Commission.
      On June 17, 1996, the Board adopted Mrs. Boudreaux's amended resolution that the Board reaffirm its commitment to help black students achieve at higher levels and endorse the "Blueprint for Action" document as a comprehensive guide to assist school communities in raising achievement for black students.
      During the June 17, 1996 "This Week In Education," Mrs. Bourdreaux announced that many Board members attended COBA's 21st Annual Black Child Conference and Attorney General Janet Reno visited Marvin Avenue School.
      On July 1, 1996, the Board held a special meeting to adopt Ms. Korenstein's amended motion that the Board strongly oppose the repeal of the statutes that assure reimbursement of the costs of desegregation programs conducted in compliance with court orders or voluntarily to avoid imposition of a court order.
      On July 15, 1996, speakers from South Central Youth Empowered thru Action (SCYEA) addressed the Board regarding Mrs. Boudreaux's motion in opposition to the California Civil Rights Initiative.
    - Legal Board Reports, 1996 August 5-1996 September 3 (Box 693)
      On August 19, 1996, Ms. Castro recognized El Centro de Pueblo as an important community based organization that provides services to students who have difficulty in a regular high school environment. Ms. Castro introduced and commended Peter Shire, artist and former Belmont High School student, who benefitted El Centro de Pueblo through the donation of his art work.
      On August 19, 1996, the Board adopted Mr. Kiriyama's amended motion regarding the restoration of the music education program for all elementary school students. During this meeting, the Board also adopted Board of Education Report No. 6, the Report from the Citizens Committee on Superintendent Selection. A copy of this report is included as an attachment to these Minutes.
    - Legal Board Reports, 1996 September 9-1996 November 25 (Box 694)
      On October 7, 1996, the Board acknowledged Proposition 187, Proposition 209, The California Civil Rights Initiative and the Gallegly Amendment as restrictive legislation concerning educational opportunities for many immigrant children and resolved to endorse the Latino Civil Rights March and Rally in Washington, D.C. on October 12, 1996.
    - Legal Board Reports, 1996 December 2-1997 February 10 (Box 695)
      On December 2, 1996, Mr. Tokofsky moved that the Board adjourn the meeting in memory of Ms. Brenda Hughes, a Franklin High School student who was tragically shot. On January 27, 1997, the Board adopted Mr. Slavkin's resolution that the Superintendent be directed to communicate in writing to the Governor and the District's legislative delegation that it is imperative that the Class Size Reduction Program be fully funded in the 1997-98 State budget.
    - Legal Board Reports, 1997 February 10-1997 March 31 (Box 696)
      On February 10, 1997, Student Member Sergio VIlla encouraged all students and parents to work together in support of Proposition BB so that students can work in a safe and clean environment.
      On February 10, 1997, the Board adopted Mr. Slavkin's substitute reading program motion for Mrs. Boudreaux's motion. This resolution includes a review of existing programs which seek to help African American students master standard English, including a determination of which have proven most effective.
      On March 31, 1997, the Board adopted Ms. Korenstein's motion regarding the California PTA's 100th Anniversary.
    - Legal Board Reports, 1997 April 7-1997 April 21 (Box 697)
      On April 21, 1997, the Board adopted Board of Education Report No. 2 as amended, The Belmont Learning Complex Project and Disposition and Development Agreement with Temple-Beaudry Partners to Construct Career Development Partnership High School Portion of Project. A copy of this report is attached to these Minutes.
    - Legal Board Reports, 1997 April 23-1997 June 16 (Box 698)
      At a special meeting on June 10, 1997, the Board adopted the receipt of the resubmitted implementation plans 1 and 2 regarding the Chanda Smith Consent Decree and Process for Review and Action. On June 16, 1997, Ms. Jo Ann Semon representing the American Indian Commission addressed the Board to express "School Mascot" concerns.
    - Legal Board Reports, 1997 June 17-1997 September 2 (Box 699)
      On July 21, 1997, the Board adopted Mr. Kiriyama's motion that the Board strongly support Federal Senate Bill 882 as introduced by California's United States Senator Barbara Boxer. On July 28, 1997, the Board held a special meeting concerning the Class Size Reduction Program.